

Ignacio Baldriz

Career Summary

Ignacio is a SSr. Data Scientist and Magister in Sociology with specialization in research methodologies. He is principally qualified in the field of machine learning, able to work on both Python and R languages. He has more than 3 years of laboral experience linking the fields of technology, data and statistical analysis.

Summary of Qualifications

Proficient In:

- Python
- Deep Learning
- NLP

- R
- Machine Learning
- Big Data
- SQL
- Image Processing
- Stata

- SPSS
- Dashboards
- Tableau

Languages

• Spanish (native speaker)

• English (advanced)

Career History

Johnson & Johnson, Montevideo, Uruguay

Jul. 2021 – today

Data Scientist

Natural Language Processiong (NLP) project

LATU, Montevideo, Uruguay

Jul. 2019 - Mar. 2021

Ceilab coordinator

Design and test workshops that promote computational thinking.

TECHO, Montevideo, Uruguay

Dic. 2015 - Jul. 2019

Research Area Director

- Lead the National Slum Survey 2018.
- Lead the data processing of systematic field surveys.

Team Management Sub Director

Orientation, accompaniment and follow-up of the hired staff.

Education

Data Camp, online, remote

Set. 2019 - Dic. 2020

Certificate in Data Science and Certificate in Machine Learning.

ORT, Montevideo, Uruguay

Jul. 2019 -

Master Degree in Big Data - Not completed.

UdelaR - FCS, Montevideo, Uruguay Master Degree, Sociology with Specialization in Research Methodologies.

UdelaR - FCS, Montevideo, Uruguay Mar. 20161 - Jun. 2015 Bachelor's Degree, Sociology.

Mar. 2016 - Jul. 2019